[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 45-year-old man is given an oral maintenance dose of drug calculated to achieve a steady-state plasma concentration of 5 mcg/L. After dosing the patient for a sufficient amount of time to reach steady state, the average plasma concentration of drug is 10 mcg/L. A decrease in which of the following parameters may explain the higher than anticipated plasma drug concentration?",
    "options": [
      "Bioavailability",
      "Clearance",
      "Half-life",
      "Volume of distribution"
    ],
    "answer": ["Clearance"],
    "explanation": "An increase in drug clearance would lead to a decrease in drug concentration in the body. In this case, if clearance decreases, the drug would be cleared from the body more slowly, leading to higher than anticipated plasma drug concentration.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 25-year-old boy came to the clinic with a history of reading late into the night and inadequate sleep, he presented with uncontrolled twitching of the eyelids. What is the most preferable drug to use in treating this condition?",
    "options": [
      "Pilocarpine",
      "Beta bungarotoxin",
      "Succinylcholine",
      "Neostigmine",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "The condition described may be related to sleep deprivation or eye strain, and it doesn't typically require drug treatment. Lifestyle changes and proper sleep hygiene may be more appropriate.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 60-year-old woman with a history of GERD presents with worsening heartburn and regurgitation. She has been taking proton pump inhibitors (PPIs) for several years but finds that her symptoms are not adequately controlled. The healthcare provider suspects the involvement of histamine receptors in her condition. What is the mechanism of action of the likely receptor subtype?",
    "options": [
      "Increase in intracellular diacylglycerol levels.",
      "Increase in intracellular cAMP levels.",
      "Increase in intracellular cGMP levels.",
      "Opening of ligand-gated hydrogen ion channels.",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Increase in intracellular cAMP levels."],
    "explanation": "The likely receptor subtype involved is an H2 receptor, which, when activated, increases intracellular cAMP levels. This leads to increased acid secretion by parietal cells, which can exacerbate GERD symptoms.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is useful in the treatment of panic attacks?",
    "options": [
      "Tricyclic antidepressants",
      "SSRIs",
      "Monoamine receptor antagonist",
      "Mixed 5HT & NE reuptake inhibitors"
    ],
    "answer": ["Mixed 5HT & NE reuptake inhibitors"],
    "explanation": "Medications that affect both serotonin (5HT) and norepinephrine (NE) reuptake can be effective in the treatment of panic attacks. They help regulate neurotransmitter levels associated with anxiety and panic.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 38-year-old patient with a long history of migraines presents with persistent headaches. Which preventive medication is most appropriate for this individual?",
    "options": ["Triptans", "NSAIDs", "Beta-blockers", "Antipsychotics"],
    "answer": ["Beta-blockers"],
    "explanation": "Beta-blockers are commonly used for migraine prophylaxis in individuals with frequent or persistent migraines.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "The following are incorrect about Epilepsy except:",
    "options": [
      "Paroxysmal derangement of cerebellar function",
      "Caused by asynchronous neuronal activity",
      "Can only be diagnosed following 2 or more seizure events caused by a medical condition",
      "Seizure events do not always involve involuntary movement of the entire body or isolated muscle groups"
    ],
    "answer": ["Paroxysmal derangement of cerebellar function"],
    "explanation": "Epilepsy is not associated with paroxysmal derangement of cerebellar function. It involves recurrent seizures due to abnormal neuronal activity in the brain.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 78-year-old woman is started on digoxin for the management of congestive heart failure. Her initial dose is 0.25 mg. The plasma concentration obtained by extrapolation of the elimination phase is determined to be 0.05 mg/L. What is the patient's estimated volume of distribution?",
    "options": ["0.0125 L", "0.2 L", "0.5 L", "1 L", "5 L"],
    "answer": ["0.5 L"],
    "explanation": "The estimated volume of distribution (Vd) is calculated by dividing the amount of drug in the body (dose) by the plasma concentration. In this case, Vd = Dose / Concentration = 0.25 mg / 0.05 mg/L = 0.5 L.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 5-year-old boy in a war-torn region presents to the emergency room with pupillary constriction, sialorrhea, hyperhidrosis, and respiratory depression. What is the drug of choice for treating this condition?",
    "options": [
      "Neostigmine",
      "Atracurium",
      "Abenonium",
      "Naloxone",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Naloxone"],
    "explanation": "The symptoms described are consistent with opioid toxicity. Naloxone is the drug of choice for reversing opioid overdose and its associated effects, including respiratory depression.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Cannabinoids, both endogenous and exogenous, have potential medical applications due to their interaction with the endocannabinoid system. Which of the following is an endocannabinoid produced naturally by the human body?",
    "options": [
      "Tetrahydrocannabinol",
      "Cannabidiol",
      "Anandamide",
      "Cannabinol",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Anandamide"],
    "explanation": "Anandamide is an endogenous cannabinoid produced naturally by the human body. It plays a role in the endocannabinoid system and has potential medical applications.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 62 years old man who was said to be bereaved and was placed on some medication. A few weeks later he presented to the urology clinic with complaints of urinary retention. What's the most likely drug?",
    "options": ["Fluoxetine", "Sertraline", "Imipramine", "Trazodone"],
    "answer": ["Imipramine"],
    "explanation": "Imipramine is a tricyclic antidepressant that can cause anticholinergic side effects, including urinary retention. In this case, the patient's symptoms of urinary retention may be related to the medication.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 30-year-old woman with frequent migraines is planning to become pregnant. What is the most suitable migraine prophylaxis for her at this stage?",
    "options": ["Topiramate", "Propranolol", "Valproate", "NSAIDs"],
    "answer": ["NSAIDs"],
    "explanation": "During pregnancy planning, it's important to consider the safety of medications. NSAIDs are a more suitable option for migraine prophylaxis in this case as they are generally considered safer during pregnancy compared to some other migraine medications.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following first-line agents is incorrectly matched?",
    "options": [
      "Tonic Clonic seizures -- Lamotrigine",
      "Status Epilepticus --- Fosphenytoin",
      "Absence seizures -- Carbamazepine",
      "Partial seizures -- Valproic acid"
    ],
    "answer": ["Absence seizures -- Carbamazepine"],
    "explanation": "Carbamazepine is not a first-line treatment for absence seizures. Valproic acid is the preferred first-line agent for treating absence seizures.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which subfamily of cytochrome P-450s is responsible for the highest fraction of clinically important drug interactions resulting from metabolism?",
    "options": ["CYP1A", "CYP2A", "CYP3A", "CYP4A", "CYP5A"],
    "answer": ["CYP3A"],
    "explanation": "CYP3A is responsible for the highest fraction of clinically important drug interactions resulting from metabolism. It plays a significant role in drug metabolism in the liver and can lead to various drug interactions.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "An 80-year-old man presents with features of dementia and was diagnosed with Alzheimer's disease. The following drugs are currently used in treating this condition except",
    "options": [
      "Rivastigmine",
      "Galantamine",
      "Tacrine",
      "Donepezil",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["None of the above"],
    "explanation": "All the mentioned drugs, Rivastigmine, Galantamine, Tacrine, and Donepezil, are used in the treatment of Alzheimer's disease. Therefore, none of the above is the correct answer.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the difference between CB1 and CB2 receptors in the endocannabinoid system?",
    "options": [
      "CB1 receptors are primarily found in the immune system, while CB2 receptors are located in the central nervous system.",
      "CB1 receptors are mainly found in the brain and central nervous system, while CB2 receptors are primarily located in the immune system and peripheral tissues.",
      "CB1 and CB2 receptors have identical distribution in the body.",
      "CB1 receptors are responsible for the immune response and mood regulation, while CB2 receptors are nonfunctional.",
      "None of the above."
    ],
    "answer": [
      "CB1 receptors are mainly found in the brain and central nervous system, while CB2 receptors are primarily located in the immune system and peripheral tissues."
    ],
    "explanation": "CB1 receptors are mainly found in the brain and central nervous system, while CB2 receptors are primarily located in the immune system and peripheral tissues. This distribution accounts for their different functions.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following is correctly Matched?",
    "options": [
      "milnacipra --> neuropathic pain",
      "duloxetine --> fibromyalgia",
      "venlafaxine --> insomnia",
      "desvenlafaxine --> anxiety disorder"
    ],
    "answer": ["duloxetine --> fibromyalgia"],
    "explanation": "Duloxetine is correctly matched with fibromyalgia. It is used for the treatment of fibromyalgia among other indications.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 45-year-old patient with migraines has contraindications to standard migraine prophylactic medications. Which non-pharmacological approach can be considered for migraine management in this case?",
    "options": [
      "Avoiding dietary triggers",
      "Physical therapy",
      "Acupuncture",
      "Intravenous triptan therapy"
    ],
    "answer": ["Acupuncture"],
    "explanation": "In cases where standard migraine prophylactic medications are contraindicated, non-pharmacological approaches like acupuncture can be considered for migraine management.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "During a routine hospital visit, a young mother complains that her 15-month-old child is easily distracted, staring off into one direction for up to 30 seconds at a time, before resuming normal play/activities. During these periods of distraction, she does not respond when called. On examination, the child is found to be healthy, with good auditory response, and speech control appropriate to her age. She was diagnosed with a seizure disorder. Which of these agents would be best for management",
    "options": ["Ethosuximide", "Valproic acid", "Carbamazepine", "Retigabine"],
    "answer": ["Ethosuximide"],
    "explanation": "Ethosuximide is a commonly used medication for the management of absence seizures, which is a type of seizure described in the case of the young child. It is the preferred treatment for this seizure type.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "24-year-old female is prescribed erythromycin for gastroparesis. It is prescribed four times daily due to its short half-life. What is the rationale for such a frequent dosing?",
    "options": [
      "Achieve the steady-state plasma concentration of the drug",
      "Aid more complete distribution of the drug",
      "Avoid the toxicity of the drug because of its low therapeutic index",
      "Ensure that the drug concentration remains constant over time",
      "Inhibit the first-pass metabolism of the drug"
    ],
    "answer": ["Ensure that the drug concentration remains constant over time"],
    "explanation": "Erythromycin is prescribed four times daily due to its short half-life to ensure that the drug concentration remains constant over time. This frequent dosing maintains an effective concentration for the treatment of gastroparesis.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 45-year-old woman who was to undergo surgery was given suxamethonium and she started fasciculating. What kind of adverse effect is she experiencing",
    "options": [
      "Bizarre",
      "Genetic",
      "Augmented",
      "Chronic",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Augmented"],
    "explanation": "The woman is experiencing an augmented adverse effect due to suxamethonium administration. Augmentation is characterized by an increase in intensity or duration of expected side effects.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "During which phase of clinical trials are drugs tested on a larger group of patients to determine their safety, efficacy, and optimal dosages?",
    "options": [
      "Phase 1",
      "Phase 2",
      "Phase 3",
      "Phase 4",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Phase 3"],
    "explanation": "During Phase 3 of clinical trials, drugs are tested on a larger group of patients to determine their safety, efficacy, and optimal dosages before they are approved for widespread use.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Components of SSRI discontinuation syndrome except",
    "options": [
      "Suicidal ideation",
      "Hypertensive crisis",
      "Gastrointestinal flu-like syndrome",
      "Insomnia"
    ],
    "answer": ["Hypertensive crisis"],
    "explanation": "Hypertensive crisis is not typically a component of SSRI discontinuation syndrome. The other options mentioned can be part of this syndrome, but hypertensive crisis is not a common symptom.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 50-year-old patient has been diagnosed with migraine with aura and a history of coronary artery disease. What acute migraine medication should be avoided due to the risk of coronary vasospasm?",
    "options": ["Triptans", "NSAIDs", "Ergotamines", "Opioid analgesics"],
    "answer": ["Ergotamines"],
    "explanation": "Ergotamines should be avoided in patients with a history of coronary artery disease, as they carry a risk of causing coronary vasospasm, which could be dangerous for such patients.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "General anesthesia induces the following states, except:",
    "options": [
      "Loss of reflexes",
      "Loss of inhibition",
      "Loss of consciousness",
      "Loss of muscle tone"
    ],
    "answer": ["Loss of inhibition"],
    "explanation": "General anesthesia induces loss of reflexes, consciousness, and muscle tone. However, it does not necessarily induce loss of inhibition.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 35-year-old woman is started on ceftriaxone as empiric therapy for meningitis. Following intravenous administration, the initial rates of drug distribution to different tissues depend primarily on which of the following parameters?",
    "options": [
      "Active transport of the drug out of different cell types",
      "Blood flow to the tissues",
      "Degree of ionization of the drug in the tissues",
      "Fat content of the tissues",
      "Specific organ clearances"
    ],
    "answer": ["Blood flow to the tissues"],
    "explanation": "The initial rates of drug distribution to different tissues depend primarily on blood flow to the tissues. The circulation helps transport the drug to various body regions.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 45-year-old woman presented to the clinic with a history of fluctuating fatigable muscle weakness that worsens with activity and improves on rest and was diagnosed with myasthenia gravis, which of the following drugs are contraindicated in this patient",
    "options": [
      "Oxprenolol",
      "Lithium",
      "Polymyxin B",
      "Ciprofloxacin",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["All of the above"],
    "explanation": "All of the mentioned drugs, Oxprenolol, Lithium, Polymyxin B, and Ciprofloxacin, are contraindicated in a patient with myasthenia gravis due to their potential to worsen muscle weakness.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "What is the term for a placebo-controlled trial in which neither the researchers nor the participants know who is receiving the experimental drug and who is receiving the placebo?",
    "options": [
      "Single-blind trial",
      "Double-blind trial",
      "Triple-blind trial",
      "Open-label trial",
      "Cross-sectional trial"
    ],
    "answer": ["Double-blind trial"],
    "explanation": "A double-blind trial is a placebo-controlled trial in which neither the researchers nor the participants know who is receiving the experimental drug and who is receiving the placebo. This design helps reduce bias in the study.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A patient who had been on fluoxetine for depression visits another doctor where he was placed on isocarboxazid. Which of the following drugs would NOT be useful in the management of the possible interaction",
    "options": ["Propranolol", "Diazepam", "Citalopram", "Cyproheptadine"],
    "answer": ["Citalopram"],
    "explanation": "Citalopram would not be useful in the management of the possible interaction between fluoxetine and isocarboxazid, as it is also an antidepressant and may not address the interaction concern.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 45-year-old patient with treatment-resistant schizophrenia is prescribed a second-generation antipsychotic. What atypical antipsychotic agent is known for its limited propensity to cause metabolic side effects?",
    "options": ["Aripiprazole", "Olanzapine", "Clozapine", "Risperidone"],
    "answer": ["Aripiprazole"],
    "explanation": "Aripiprazole is known for its limited propensity to cause metabolic side effects compared to other second-generation antipsychotics. It is often used in cases where metabolic side effects are a concern.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "About inhaled anesthetic agents, which is incorrect:",
    "options": [
      "Drugs with a low blood: gas coefficient have a faster onset of action",
      "Pulmonary blood flow is directly proportional to onset of action",
      "Drug action is terminated by redistribution to and elimination by the lungs",
      "The concentration of the agent that eliminates the response to a standardized painful stimulus in 50% of patients is the best measure of potency"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "The concentration of the agent that eliminates the response to a standardized painful stimulus in 50% of patients is the best measure of potency"
    ],
    "explanation": "The concentration of the agent that eliminates the response to a standardized painful stimulus in 50% of patients is not the best measure of potency for inhaled anesthetic agents. Instead, the blood: gas coefficient is often used as a measure of potency.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which of the following terms is used to describe the elimination rate via metabolism catalyzed by alcohol dehydrogenase when the enzyme is saturated?",
    "options": [
      "Biotransformation",
      "Clearance",
      "First-order elimination",
      "Redistribution",
      "Zero-order kinetics"
    ],
    "answer": ["Zero-order kinetics"],
    "explanation": "Zero-order kinetics is used to describe the elimination rate via metabolism catalyzed by alcohol dehydrogenase when the enzyme is saturated. In zero-order kinetics, the elimination rate is constant regardless of the drug concentration.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 50-year-old man with hypertension was prescribed a drug and upon taking the drug he lost consciousness 45 minutes after. Which of the following drugs is notorious for this phenomenon",
    "options": [
      "Phentolamine",
      "Prazosin",
      "Phenoxybenzamine",
      "Tamsulosin",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Prazosin"],
    "explanation": "Prazosin is notorious for causing a phenomenon known as 'first-dose hypotension,' where a patient with hypertension may experience a sudden drop in blood pressure, leading to loss of consciousness after taking the drug.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which regulatory pathway allows for accelerated approval of drugs for serious conditions based on surrogate endpoints rather than clinical outcomes, and requires post-marketing studies to confirm efficacy?",
    "options": [
      "Orphan Drug Designation",
      "Fast Track Designation",
      "Breakthrough Therapy Designation",
      "Priority Review",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Breakthrough Therapy Designation"],
    "explanation": "The Breakthrough Therapy Designation regulatory pathway allows for accelerated approval of drugs for serious conditions based on surrogate endpoints. However, post-marketing studies are required to confirm efficacy.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Which drug has been implicated in Disulfiram reaction",
    "options": ["Propranolol", "Metronidazole", "Vancomycin", "Baclofen"],
    "answer": ["Metronidazole"],
    "explanation": "Metronidazole is a drug that has been implicated in Disulfiram reaction when consumed with alcohol. This reaction includes symptoms like flushing, nausea, and vomiting.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 35-year-old patient with schizophrenia and a history of cardiac arrhythmias is started on an antipsychotic. Which class of antipsychotics should be avoided due to the risk of QT prolongation?",
    "options": [
      "First-generation antipsychotics",
      "Second-generation antipsychotics",
      "Third-generation antipsychotics",
      "Benzodiazepines"
    ],
    "answer": ["Second-generation antipsychotics"],
    "explanation": "Second-generation antipsychotics should be avoided in a patient with a history of cardiac arrhythmias due to the risk of QT prolongation. They can lead to potentially dangerous heart rhythm disturbances.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Effects of local anesthetic agents",
    "options": [
      "Amides are more predisposed to cause allergic reactions than Esters",
      "Methemoglobinemia is a side effect of Bupivacaine",
      "Side effects of cocaine are due to vasodilation",
      "Myelinated nerves are blocked faster than unmyelinated"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Amides are more predisposed to cause allergic reactions than Esters"
    ],
    "explanation": "Amides are generally more predisposed to cause allergic reactions compared to Esters. Allergies to local anesthetic agents are more commonly associated with amides.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "If the oral dosing rate of a drug is held constant, what will occur if the bioavailability is increased?",
    "options": [
      "Decreased first-order elimination rate constant",
      "Decreased total body clearance",
      "Increased half-life for first-order elimination",
      "Increased steady-state plasma concentration",
      "Increased volume of distribution"
    ],
    "answer": ["Increased steady-state plasma concentration"],
    "explanation": "If the oral dosing rate of a drug is held constant and bioavailability is increased, there will be an increased steady-state plasma concentration of the drug in the body. This is because more of the administered dose reaches the systemic circulation.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 26-year-old woman came to the O&G clinic with premature labor, which of the following agents can be used to delay it",
    "options": [
      "Dopamine",
      "Pseudoephedrine",
      "Ritodrine",
      "Phenylephrine",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Ritodrine"],
    "explanation": "Ritodrine can be used to delay premature labor. It is a tocolytic agent that helps relax the uterine muscles and delay labor.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "What phase of drug development typically involves testing a drug in a small number of healthy volunteers to assess its safety and pharmacokinetics?",
    "options": [
      "Phase 1",
      "Phase 2",
      "Phase 3",
      "Phase 4",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Phase 1"],
    "explanation": "Phase 1 of drug development typically involves testing a drug in a small number of healthy volunteers to assess its safety, pharmacokinetics, and dosing. This phase helps determine how the drug is tolerated and metabolized in humans.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Tyramine toxicity can be induced by one of the following drugs",
    "options": ["Selegiline", "Imipramine", "Fluoxetine", "Cyproheptadine"],
    "answer": ["Selegiline"],
    "explanation": "Tyramine toxicity can be induced by selegiline. This drug is an MAO-B inhibitor and can lead to an accumulation of tyramine, potentially causing hypertensive crisis when tyramine-containing foods are consumed.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 50-year-old patient with schizophrenia and a high risk of tardive dyskinesia due to prior antipsychotic use is being evaluated for a new medication. What second-generation antipsychotic has the lowest risk of causing tardive dyskinesia?",
    "options": ["Risperidone", "Quetiapine", "Aripiprazole", "Ziprasidone"],
    "answer": ["Aripiprazole"],
    "explanation": "Aripiprazole has the lowest risk of causing tardive dyskinesia among second-generation antipsychotics. It is considered a safer choice for patients at high risk of developing tardive dyskinesia.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Parkinson's disease:",
    "options": [
      "Is a possible complication of Wilson's disease, Cyanide poisoning, or traumatic brain injury",
      "Symptoms present when 80% of the basal ganglia adrenergic neurons have degenerated",
      "Dopamine is degraded by MAO-A and COMT to homovanillic acid",
      "Lewy bodies are pathognomonic"
    ],
    "answer": [
      "Is a possible complication of Wilson's disease, Cyanide poisoning, or traumatic brain injury"
    ],
    "explanation": "Parkinson's disease is a possible complication of Wilson's disease, cyanide poisoning, or traumatic brain injury. It can be a secondary condition in these cases.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 38-year-old woman presents to her psychiatrist for the management of depression. She feels that her current treatment is ineffective and would like to switch medications. The patient reveals that she drinks alcohol every night to relieve her feelings of sadness and guilt. Blood work is positive for elevated liver enzymes. The doctor starts imipramine, which has an extensive first-pass metabolism. How would this drug be affected?",
    "options": [
      "Decreased half-life",
      "Decreased absorption",
      "Decreased solubility",
      "Increased concentration",
      "Increased pH"
    ],
    "answer": ["Increased concentration"],
    "explanation": "Imipramine, with its extensive first-pass metabolism, will have increased concentration in the body when the liver's ability to metabolize it is impaired, as indicated by elevated liver enzymes due to alcohol use.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 55-year-old patient presented to the clinic with the following symptoms; frequent urge to urinate, frequent urination, bed wetting, bladder spasm and leaking of urine. He was diagnosed of spastic bladder. Which of the following is used in the management of this condition",
    "options": [
      "Hyoscine butylbromide",
      "Benzhexol",
      "Propanthelin",
      "Pirenzepine",
      "Hyoscine"
    ],
    "answer": ["Hyoscine butylbromide"],
    "explanation": "Hyoscine butylbromide is used in the management of spastic bladder. It helps to relieve symptoms such as frequent urination, bladder spasm, and leakage of urine in conditions like overactive bladder.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "In the drug development process, what does the term 'IND' stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Investigational New Drug",
      "International New Development",
      "Investigative Novel Drug",
      "Investigational New Database",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["Investigational New Drug"],
    "explanation": "In the drug development process, 'IND' stands for 'Investigational New Drug.' This term is used to describe a new drug that is being investigated in clinical trials.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "One of the following statements best describes the MOA of amphetamine",
    "options": [
      "Inhibits phosphodiesterase",
      "Inhibits catecholamines",
      "Blocks NMDA receptor",
      "Agonist at 5-HT2A receptor"
    ],
    "answer": ["Inhibits catecholamines"],
    "explanation": "Amphetamine primarily works by increasing the release of catecholamines, such as dopamine and norepinephrine, and inhibiting their reuptake. This leads to increased stimulation and alertness.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 28-year-old patient with schizophrenia is experiencing severe cognitive deficits. Which antipsychotic medication, sometimes considered for its potential cognitive-enhancing effects, may be suitable for this case?",
    "options": ["Olanzapine", "Haloperidol", "Clozapine", "Lurasidone"],
    "answer": ["Lurasidone"],
    "explanation": "Lurasidone is an antipsychotic medication that is sometimes considered for its potential cognitive-enhancing effects. It may be suitable for a patient with schizophrenia experiencing severe cognitive deficits.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "Concerning the Nigrostriatal pathways:",
    "options": [
      "Its neurons synapse directly on the spinal motor neurons to control movement",
      "The direct pathway initiates movement when activated",
      "Ballismus and intention tremors are a result of damage to the direct pathway",
      "The Globus pallidus externa plays a key role in the direct pathway"
    ],
    "answer": ["The direct pathway initiates movement when activated"],
    "explanation": "In the basal ganglia's Nigrostriatal pathways, the direct pathway initiates movement when activated. Dysfunction in this pathway can lead to movement disorders.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "A 55-year-old man recently diagnosed with Parkinson’s disease complains of nausea when using the prescribed medication. This side effect is likely mediated at:",
    "options": [
      "Amygdala",
      "Paraventricular nucleus",
      "Area postrema",
      "Occipital cortex"
    ],
    "answer": ["Area postrema"],
    "explanation": "Nausea, often a side effect of Parkinson's disease medications, is likely mediated at the area postrema, a region in the brain that plays a role in vomiting and nausea control.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "questionType": "objective",
    "question": "In the management of Parkinson’s disease, Tolcapone is often combined with Levodopa because it:",
    "options": [
      "Increases the t½ of Levodopa",
      "Inhibits intracerebral metabolism of Levodopa",
      "Delays the onset of bradykinesia improvement",
      "Eliminates the on-off effect"
    ],
    "answer": ["Inhibits intracerebral metabolism of Levodopa"],
    "explanation": "Tolcapone is often combined with Levodopa in the management of Parkinson's disease because it inhibits the intracerebral metabolism of Levodopa, increasing its availability and duration of action.",
    "searchTags": [],
    "sources": ["PHARMACOLOGY CMDA Med180 2nd test"],
    "topics": [""],
    "course": "Pharmacology",
    "subcourse": null,
    "numberOfAttempts": 0,
    "averageUnderstanding": 0.0,
    "previous10AttemptQuestionscore": [],
    "averageUnderstandingRatePer10": [],
    "iscompleted": false,
    "averagerating": 0,
    "variationgiven": 0
  }
]
